Alexandru Grajdeanu

Bucharest, Romania \bowtie grajdeanu.alex@gmail.com

Summary

Rock-solid software engineer, always interested in the latest trends and research efforts in computer science, with over 5 years experience in both designing and programming across a variety of platforms. While mostly focused on Python/Django, I'm constantly writing small C / C++ programs. Beside this, I take care of random projects over the internet. I also have a deep interest in cyber security field.

Technical Skills

- Programming languages: Python, JS, ReactJS + Redux, C, Magik
- Frameworks: Django (DRF), Flask, Tornado
- Networking: vast knowledge of several protocols as BGP, MPLS, IS-IS, OSPF, UDP -TCP/IP, SNMP(v2c/v3)
- Network administration: Infosim StableNET, Zenoss
- Shell lover: Bash (sh, zsh) vim, batch
- Revision control and code review platforms: GIT, SVN
- Others: JIRA (Agile) / Confluence (documentation)

Experience

July Senior Software Developer, Cegeka, Bucharest, Romania.

2017-Present Full stack application development using Django REST Framework, ReactJS, Redux, Webpack, Semantic-UI, PostgreSQL, MSSQL and Node is on internal applications with a focus on hardware monitoring - development of all server-side logic, ensuring high performance and responsiveness to requests from the front-end.

January Freelance Developer, Upwork.com, Bucharest, Romania.

2014-Present

Working with clients all over the world making sure that their ideas come to life. I have mainly worked as a full stack developer, on projects of all scales (small, medium and large). I've handled every aspect of implementation on each project that I've worked on, from setting up a VPS with the required dependencies, to designing the application architecture and data model, as well as taking care of frontend/backend development.

October Software Applications Developer Engineer, Orange Romania, Bucharest, Romania.

2016–Jul Software development based on the GE Smallworld GIS product suite using Magik, which is an OO programming language derived from Smalltalk, quite similar to Ruby or Python.

November Software Engineer, Datanet Systems, Bucharest, Romania.

2015— I've been developing modular web applications from scratch (mainly NMSs - Network Management Systems) using Python, Perl, JS and some APIs as well as building cross-platform automation scripts using Shell or Python. More, I've consolidated my networking knowledge about some protocols: SNMP, BGP, IS-IS, MPLS and OSPF.

April 2015— **Python and Django Developer**, *Tri-Ant Tehnologies Limited*, Bucharest, Romania. November Developing clean and reliable web applications using Python and frameworks such as Django as

well as building clean and reliable REST APIs.

Education

2011–2015 Bachelor of Science, University Politehnica of Bucharest.

Certifications

- o FCE First Certificate of English
- Infosim Certified Engineer (ICE)
- o ORACLE Database Administration

Miscellaneous

- I'm a perfectionist with a strong passion for clean code, great software, space exploration and astronomy. I like to break things, to find new ways to break things, to solve problems, to put things under test and stress, and to have my mind blown by an interesting question
- Open source contributions: answering / reviewing code on Codereview Stackexchange community.
- o Various prizes at informatics and phisycs competitions during high-school